KAZI MOSHIUR RAHAMAN

Address: Bashundhara R/A, Dhaka-1229, Bangladesh.

LinkedIn URL: www.linkedin.com/in/kazi-moshiur-rahaman-665360186/
Email: moshiur.mubin0@gmail.com
Contact no: 01835601652

Date of Birth: 11th May 1997

Career Objective

Goal oriented, focused, energetic computer science specialist skilled in Machine Learning, Deep learning, Data visualization and analysis, also creative thinker who has thirst to utilize his time with accruing new knowledge and help to achieve goals of the organization with team.

Education

Masters in Applied Statistics & Data Science from Jahangirnagar University	-2024
B.Sc. in Computer Science and Engineering from North South University	- 2021
Specialized Trail - Artificial Intelligence	
Higher Secondary School Certificate (HSC) from Notre Dame College	-2016
Group – Science	
Secondary School Certificate (SSC) from Udayan Uchcha Madhyamik Bidyalaya	-2014
Group – Science	

Experiences

Daraz Bangladesh

-Data Analyst April 2022 -Dec 2023

KPIs: Customer NPS. Reverse Leadtime, IPO

- Convert raw data into actionable insights by predicting and modelling future outcomes to enhance customer experience.
- Furnish insights, analytics, and business intelligence needed to guide decisions for future projects.
- Developed BI Report and Dashboard using Alibaba's in-house Data Visualization Software
- Overseeing Customer Experience Projects, specifically working on improvement of customer claim

Tools: SQL,Python,Power BI,Excel

Flatknit International Ltd

-Junior Developer Oct 2021 - Feb 2022

Projects: Ecommerce Site, Website

- Worked with the developer team and build their website, e-commerce site
- Analyzed the social media market and regularly update on there
- Communicated with customers, delivery team and vigilant over the store products

Tools: Wordpress, Excel, Google Analytics

ICS System Solution (Internship)

-Junior Developer & QA Engineer Jan 2021 – June 2021

Projects: SCM software - Garment, Asset management software - Bank

- Worked with the developing team as jr. developer
- Met with authorities and end-users to get their requirements and make documentation
- · Analyzed, designed, made documentation and submitted those to the developing team
- Tested the regular update of software given by developer
- Took training session on regular basis to explain the function of the software to the clients and users

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: Python, C

• Framework: Django,

• Libraries: TensorFlow, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib

• Database Tools: MySQL

• Analytics tools: Tableau, MS Excel

• Others: Machine learning, Deep learning tools

Extra-Curricular Activities:

- 1)Runner up, Udayan School Intra Science Fair and volunteered on different cultural & academic programs.
- 2)Member and volunteered at 'বিশ্ব সাহিত্য কেন্দ্ৰ'/'Bissho Shahitto Kendro'
- 3) Member at Norte Dame College Science Club
- 4)General Member at NSU Computer & Engineering Club
 - Volunteered and participated at Cybernauts and In-house Robotics Competition.
- 5)Executive body Member (Treasurer) at NSU Public Health & Sciences Club
 - Organized World Health Fest, Diabetics Day, Self-Developing Workshops
 - Arranged live seminars during Covid-19
 - Supervised on club program budget and sponsorship papers

References:

Name	Designation	Organization	Email
Fahim Jawad	Head of Strategy,CXP	Daraz Bangladesh LTD	Fahim.jawad@daraz.com.bd
Kazi Siam Alam	Manager,CXP	Daraz Bangladesh LTD	Siam.alam@daraz.com.bd